Frank Bolle Cartoons
Frank Bolle Cartoons
1966-1969
Bolle, Frank
6 linear ft.
Original daily and Sunday cartoons from the newspaper comic strip Debbie Deere.
2642143
Biographical History
Frank Bolle (1924- ) is an American cartoonist and illustrator.
Frank Bolle was born in New York City on June 7, 1924. After service with the U.S. Army Air Forces during World War II, Bolle attended the Pratt Institute, graduating with honors. His initial professional work included illustrating westerns, science fiction comics and adventure stories for Magazine Enterprises, Western Publishing, Boys' Life and others. Bolle also worked on a number of newspaper comic strips over the course of his prolific career. Debbie Deere may have been his first high profile newspaper feature, but it was short-lived (1966-1969). Subsequently, Bolle has left his mark on many prominent newspaper strips, including The Heart of Juliet Jones (1982-1999), Winnie Winkle (1983-2003) and Apartment 3-G (1999- ). Frank Bolle was recognized with an Inkpot Award at the 2003 San Diego Comic-Con, in recognition of his lifetime of achievement in comics.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Frank Bolle Cartoons collection contains 953 original daily cartoons and 113 original Sunday cartoons from the newspaper comic strip Debbie Deere (1966-1969). Daily cartoon: traces of graphite, opaque white, pasteovers, brush, pen and ink on illustration board, approx. 7 x 19 in. Sunday cartoon: traces of graphite, opaque white, pasteovers, brush, pen and ink on illustration board, approx. 15 ½ x 21 ½ in.
Arrangement of the Collection
Daily and Sunday cartoons are arranged separately in chronological order.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Bolle, Frank.; McNaught Syndicate.; Debbie Deere (comic strip); Art -- Cartoonists; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Comic books, strips, etc. -- United States.; Cartoons (humorous images); Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Frank Bolle, 1967-1969.
Inventory
- Debbie Deere, 1,066
  Click here for detailed inventory.
  - Daily cartoons, 953
    - 1966 May - 1966 Oct (Box 1)
    - 1966 Nov - 1967 Mar (Box 2)
    - 1967 Apr - 1967 Sep (Box 3)
    - 1967 Oct - 1968 Apr (Box 4)
    - 1968 May - 1968 Nov (Box 5)
    - 1968 Dec - 1969 Aug (Box 6)
  - Sunday cartoons, 113
    - 1966 Jun - 1967 Jun (Oversize 1)
    - 1967 Jul - 1968 Aug (Oversize 2)